welcome back
our next session is about insurance and
the insurance industries we all know has
been overhauled several times in fact if
i had a premium for every time the
insurance industry has been overhauled
it would still be too high there's often
an article decrying millennials like
myself that we are not buying enough
insurance so why are we not buying i
don't know no one is asked but in this
space as with every other space and
we've seen a lot of this over the
conference there's tremendous growth and
scope for innovation so here we have the
next panel about innovation in insurance
so please allow me and join me in
welcoming on stage uh vijay kumar the
ceo of go digit general insurance
limited annual vice president id icici
lombard abhishek podar co-founder and
ceo of plum praveen kumar b head of
information ahead of innovation sorry
with star health insurance chennai
ghosha
sonic host ceo and executive director of
vice general insurance and sagar success
founding team and senior director
enterprise marketing for razorback thank
you guys so much for giving us your time
looking forward to the session take it
away stand up
thank you so much
welcome welcome everyone to ftx 2021 um
this this session is very close to you
know a lot of people considering the
times uh and uh you know i'm kind of
super excited and privileged to kind of
uh uh getting this opportunity to uh you
know moderate the session with such you
know such such wonderful panelists so
i'll try and make sure that uh i i keep
you know minimal time to myself and uh
try and navigate through a lot of uh you
know pointers that i have in mind and
without further ado i probably try and
you know throw the first question out
there and uh
obviously during these changing times uh
the covet times you know the first thing
which everyone kind of talks about is
that hey uh you know have you purchased
some insurance or what will happen to
you and things like that so obviously
you know there is some amount of scare
scare which is out there and uh you know
how is that impacting the entire uh uh
indian ecosystem so obviously there are
some reports that i
you know kind of uh went through and
everyone's like very good about
hey the insurance industry is going to
grow the premium collection is going to
grow
um so obviously you know want to pick
everyone's brain on this specific topic
and keeping in mind that you know where
will this growth be coming from
i mean obviously there are a lot more
people out there in india who are who
are to be insured and you know whether
this is going to come from bharat
customers indian customers uh i mean
there are a lot more questions around it
but yeah growth is probably the the
first you know pointer that i had in
mind and i'd probably throw this to uh
which is uh which is a what are your you
know what what are your thoughts on on
this specific piece
yeah thank you uh serger and uh
hello everyone uh all the viewers
um
the
i think uh
uh coved as all of us know you know uh
posed lot of challenges and uh but also
there has been a lot of learning uh
during this entire period and
a lot of company really geared up
you know to
uh
to you know meet those challenges you
know
so as such the non-life general
insurance i think fairly was not
impacted to that extent of course the
entire industry was
you know growth was
almost
negligible it was more or less flat
our company per se go digit
we grew even during uh
period also
and uh
um
because there are a lot of you know uh
automobiles there was a setback uh
travel there was you know setback
airlines were not uh
flying so
obviously uh
the premium was about to you know uh
suffer
uh
but somehow you know uh because of
um health insurance i think the
companies could sail through
uh so a lot of companies actually came
out with certain uh innovative products
and companies geared up how to you know
service the claims during uh pandemic uh
we ourselves actually
came out with certain
overt related product
right in the beginning as early as you
know
uh january for b2020
so
uh that has uh you know uh
these are kind of you know indemnity and
benefit-based uh
you know covers
because nobody knew that uh you know
what covent will behave
how it is going to behave and i know
what are the treatments involved
so the best thing was to pay a lump sum
money and
help the uh you know
patients
so
this actually helped uh
give a lot of support to all the
companies and
there was significant growth and post
coverage also i think the the momentum
is continuing uh today
industry is growing at a rate of you
know 12
and we uh and digit we are also growing
significantly
uh you know
close to 100 uh last month we grew a
hundred percent
so because of numbers
uh the various uh you know uh
uh
support you know which is flowing in
the automobile also improving the
economy is also improving
and health of course continues to you
know give support to the insurance
industry so overall things uh you know
are looking uh fine but
now only we have to see uh you know
the new variant that people are talking
about we need to be cautious but uh as
far as you know we are concerned i think
in my view um
uh since we have gone through that tough
phase and vaccination has happened
probably uh we'll be able to better
manage then
we could you know do that
last year or early this year
great great uh sir i think there are a
lot of insights that i'd probably want
to come back upon but uh i i think uh
shania i want to throw this question to
you next uh on on the you know on the
general growth trend side and uh there
are a lot of things that
we just kind of talked about in terms of
numbers as well uh would want to
understand more um from a generic
industry point of view that are you also
seeing the same sort of trends and uh is
there any such sort of new trends which
are emerging out now that we are seeing
that you know maybe the covet times are
are behind us and like sir is also
mentioning that there there might be a
chance that you know what electron is
not that uh it's not that dangerous and
now people are vaccinated so what are
your takes on on this specific point
so uh sagaran step back a little bit and
talk a little bit about the industry the
industry itself you know is just not one
when we talk about the gi or the
non-life industry its definition is
everything not life so you can imagine
how diverse and heterogeneous it is
and this is one of the reasons that you
know since liberalization since we've
been tracking it since 2000 on uh the
industry has never had a single year of
decline
and in this period the industry has gone
through you know deterrification which
is a huge
uh step it's gone through the economic
upheaval you know the
general industry has gone through life
life has gone through a huge up and a
huge down
but gi has been pretty steady state it's
sort of was the unglamorous uh sibling
of life industry but i think in the last
three four years it has come into its
own and hopefully people are realizing
the value and the importance
and truly the dynamism of the industry
so i think except for last year which
was an aberration where we grew around
for five percent and we still grew this
year we are continuing to grow like
vijay she said at around
12 percent so
and our
penetration if you look at our
penetration is around 1 right now which
is 1 4 of the global average so you know
the head room for growth is significant
there is no question um and i if you
look at the various segments that are
there in the industry whether you look
at motor uh whether you look at health
or you look at you know business
insurance home insurance
every
uh
segment has its own phase or stage of
evolution and that's a different stage
so you know coming from whether it's
going to come from bharat or it's going
to come from
india i don't know what bharat in india
is honestly let me clarify what i mean
when i say bharat i mean like small town
india i don't necessarily mean the
villages of india i mean small town
india
so
motor penetration levels are relatively
higher than health
especially in urban india and especially
in a segment called private car where
you know large most of us who own our
cars will have insurance will be very
few of us who don't have insurance but
two wheelers where the uh
you know usage of two wheelers is much
higher in bharat or commercial vehicles
which is separate segment penetration
levels are very very low which is why
the overall penetration or the uninsured
number of vehicles or percentage in
india you hear as high as 50
which is alarming right so this is where
it comes from so this segment will i
think will get its growth
in the coming years from bharat although
when we say growth we have to
understand growth within value of volume
terms because value trumps volume even
right now so volume customers will get
from bharat valley will continue to get
from india till at least
if i was to hazard a guess at least for
the next five years but health insurance
is very different health insurance
surprisingly in urban india also is
highly underpenetrated if you look at
you know the out of pocket expenses in
uh health insurance is about 60 62
percent the world average is i think 20
percent if i'm not mistaken and i also
read a statistic that out of all the
indians only about 35
to 40 percent have any sort of health
insurance coverage including government
schemes
so you know there i feel there is enough
opportunity for growth even within the
country and we just heard khan and say
that millennials like him don't have
insurance right and why don't they have
insurance and we are not
listening enough to the barriers to
adoption i would say we tried doing it
so we created a product called health
241 where we said that you know because
millennials said i'm not going to fall
ill you know
so it's money down the drain we said
okay if you don't fall in next year's
free so we try to do that to get them on
board
so i think health insurance has a
different journey home insurance is
non-existent completely so home
insurance has to start from urban india
completely
a business insurance
largely i would say urban urban agri
insurance is of course rural so
different segments of insurance have the
different
pockets or vectors of growth but growth
is undoubtedly undeniable and even in a
segment like group health insurance
which one thought that you know everyone
wears the growth look at the growth that
we're getting today and
not all the growth is from increase in
premium a lot of growth is from newer
companies and i'm sure abhishek would
vouch to that
company is waking up to the realization
that it's an important benefit to giving
give employees and we have kobe to thank
for that there is no question about it
okay
companies are coming out and saying we
want to small companies want to give
their employees health insurance they
want to give the associates health
insurance input he referred to the covet
product in 2000 march when the cobit
breakout happened last year we actually
gave covet insurance to all our drivers
and done so delivery boys which we
continue to do today because at that
point of time this was an uncertainty so
there are these things that are driving
growth so i think there are many vectors
of growth very difficult to
you know cast paint it all with one
brush and say bharat or india yeah
pockets different uh segments different
growth but growth undeniable
makes sense i think i'd probably at this
moment go to abhishek and and abhishek
being i mean plum being a partner with
razer pay on the group insurance side i
i've actually seen those aspects as well
and have realized that the amount of
growth that we've seen on that front is
definitely undeniable and what we've
seen uh
you know is something that i i probably
throw the ball to you and uh probably
you know as this thing from uh from a
general sme point of view that uh you
know how are you seeing uh from from
those aspects in terms of how the
industry is moving considering that you
know that's that's probably one of the
area of expertise for you folks
absolutely uh i think i'll very much
echo what uh
and chennai mentioned on the growth side
i'll answer this in two parts one
is
some of the observations that we had on
what is driving this growth and then
i'll come to your question on the sme
part as well so i think there are some
underlying
transformations that have happened in
the insurance industry
for the good uh during the last two
years uh
we observed four major things uh one
if you look at the speed of development
of new products insurance industry was
not known for
rapidly innovating in terms of new
insurance products
but during kobe we saw almost all
insurance companies including all the
panelists that we have
coming together to build new products
at the speed of weeks or months rather
than years uh
and vijay was talking about uh how
quickly they launched the kovi 19
product with budget right that's an
example of one such product so i think
it has changed the space of development
in this industry
the second change that happened in the
industry was the
kind of distribution that happens this
industry was very
physical agent-led distribution and what
kobe did was it really restricted
the physical meetings that someone could
do to sell insurance and then the
companies and the intermediaries were
forced to think out of the box on how to
now run their business and that's really
built a new wave of digital distribution
uh which includes how to build pricing
online how to
make policy uh purchase online how to
make policy issuance online
the third change that we observed was uh
the simplification of insurance policy
terms and communications and this was
driven by number two in a lot of ways
because you are now doing things online
there is no other way than to simplify
your insurance policy instead of 20 30
page policy documents how to give a
policy that can be explained in one
simple
mobile ui or a web ui
and we at plum also take that philosophy
to our heart right so for example one of
the things that we follow is hey we have
to build products that can be understood
by a 10 year old person rather than 30
year old person who has used insurance
and the fourth change that we saw was
the digital ecosystem that is getting
created around claims processing and one
of the fantastic examples is how the
insurance companies have finally started
accepting the fact that hey claims
should not require
physical documents and couriering the
physical document it was a painful
experience right and
there is there are reasons of why that
was required but
the industry or the technology has moved
a lot where you can actually do
everything using scanned copies for
example
and that's where the claims processing
and hence the eventual customer
experience has been transformed a lot so
those are four changes that we are
seeing that is driving a lot of growth
that uh
we we talked about right now i think in
line with that we have seen a
fundamental shift in the sme insurance
as well and the way we see sme insurance
is
see if we
fundamentally believe that in india in
the next decade or so everyone will get
health insurance right now we have to
figure out hey how does that kind of
adoption happens and there are three
ways of that adoption to happen right
one is people buying insurance on their
own number two government coming and
ensuring the people and number three
employers coming and ensuring their
employees and their family members
we are a country where we don't not a
lot of people have very high income
levels right if we actually look at the
income levels not more than 10 of the
indian population will be able to afford
health insurance on their own
which is which in itself is a very large
number we are talking about 150 million
people buying retail health insurance
compared to 33 million people that have
it right now right so it's a 5x growth
that will happen there
and the government is also taking a very
massive
uh they have taken a massive goal of
insuring 500 million people through
ayushmann power right and i sincerely
hope that will happen and that will
happen over a period of time right but
now what happens to this middle india
which is the 700 million people who
cannot buy insurance on their own
and who will not be covered by the
government as well
and there our core belief is that it is
the employer sponsored insurance for the
for the employees and for the family
members that will help us with that kind
of penetration in india and if you
reflect on any country that has very
high distribution of insurance right be
it us european countries be it a lot of
asian countries and if you see how they
achieved that kind of 100 penetration of
health insurance it was largely driven
by government-sponsored insurance or the
employer sponsored insurance and india
won't be any different and that is the
core of why we started plum in the first
place which is hey if that is the
opportunity if that is a larger
opportunity and right now the corporate
insurance or the or the group health
insurance is restricted to the very
large corporates how do we build
something how do we simplify simplify
something that can be bought by
companies of any size be it 10 employees
or thousands of employees so that
is our core belief of why we think of
the sme operation so let me let me take
the segway
to you know to praveen and we we
actually talked a lot about uh the
entire health insurance piece and uh uh
praveen i i want to uh very quickly kind
of jump to the you know to the next
topic as well and that's that's actually
around you know why is innovation
required to be honest at the first place
is it is it something which is uh you
know which is where uh uh the industry
is kind of just trying to um i mean
aspirationally chase something or is it
is it really you know is it really
required and uh um you know uh from from
that perspective i think uh you'd be in
the perfect position to kind of uh you
know take that up
yeah thanks thanks sagar and uh see i
don't need to give any background on
innovation right see if these people
like every audience everyone has an
innovation in their gene so if human
doesn't have that will not be there in
this position right obviously it is the
necessity right so why ird is coming
with a schemes like arrogance and genie
why it is coming like standard products
okay to reach to masses right so i just
give an analogy for example i just take
my personal life right so when we talk
about when i talked about everyone has
an innovation right
so being father five by two kids right
so one of my thing is i want my kids to
eat well
and uh in south india predominantly you
know idli and dosa is a common and they
say
boring idli and dosa
and how do i make them interesting right
so
i have to
look something interesting like i cut
this idli put some cheeses i make some
spread on dosa
so
what it makes is my necessity for them
to eat well i have to innovate okay when
it comes to the organizations or when it
comes to any body
for them
when they care for the customers right
so i care for kids right similarly the
organization when they care for the
customers okay with the
in terms of insurance can be agents and
customers or the department integrated
anyone whom we are
working with
so the necessity
of enabling them
brings this innovation
that's my point with respect to
innovation and there are again different
areas and how do you innovate right so
you can give offer freebies kind of
stuff engage them or
make them healthy okay you want you i
want them to take insurance insurance is
a hedge okay predominantly i want to
touch one on the
importance of insurance it's my
practical experience
when i left my job to start entrepreneur
journey
my father fell sick it's almost like a
coveted situation that time it's a
numerical right
and i have no job
but the only the insurance that helped
me
and a recent experience with one of my
friend he spent around 20 lakhs
and unfortunately he lost his mother
with no insurance cover
so you imagine a normal person
if has to go through such a pain
their entire uh financials will go for a
toss and they
will come down see that is why i think
the organizations like irda they're
coming with standard products to make
sure the insurance is affordable
and if you read the recent report of cab
journey on wild insured tech
so one of the things they suggest is
care okay convenience advice and the
reach
so this is very very important so i bang
on the advice because people should
aware see
even lot of educated people they say i'm
healthy why should i need insurance i've
been paying insurance for the last 15
years i never claimed but does it mean
that i don't need insurance no because
you never know what happens had anyone
ever predicted such like covet pandemic
we will see in our lifetime no
so
what the insurance provides is a risk
averse that means in kind of eventuality
okay
you have something to bank on that is
where predominantly most of the
insurance companies come forward and
help and irda is predominantly coming
with a lot of standardized product to
make insurance reachable to everyone
sure and uh
i mean one very interesting thing that i
figured from your uh you know your thing
is care which is convenience advice and
reach so uh on on on that front i think
the the biggest point of obviously being
the first one is convenience and uh and
everyone i i wanted to get your thoughts
uh on on this convenience piece
specifically from you know from the
point of view of uh maybe digitization
all together for you know for for how do
we
say distribute uh insurance products how
do we make sure that uh you know people
are educated about it so on on this
you know this convenience part i think
that's the that's probably the biggest
question which is out there uh what are
your thoughts that uh
you know
when we we are talking about uh
convenience how much big role will
educating the customers uh making sure
that we have a digitized journey uh you
know play and uh do you think that
that's something which is you know
currently happening or is it something
where uh
we still need to you know push the pedal
a little bit
thanks thanks uh
i mean see i i work for icc lombard it
is one of the largest private sector
insurance companies we
uh
we have a core belief that technology is
a key enabler for our business success
and we want to use technology in all
aspects of our business
and digital solutions are at the heart
of all technology innovation at this
point of time
so uh the way we go about every simple
process of of going through this
uh we have a fairly diverse product
portfolio uh you know consumers uh have
to make
complex decisions uh to very simple
decisions so that can be a
you know that the simplest decision is
when you are taking an ola ride and you
have to decide whether you want to take
an icy slumber insurance or not to
protect that
ola ride to a very extended decision
making when you are buying health
protection for your entire family
we have
and it's true for
many of my colleagues who work in the
general insurance we have diverse
product portfolio
so we
look at digital as a way of life and we
have to think and think of the customer
journey beyond just the purchase and we
have to start thinking from the entire
process how they engage with us how they
um how they actually buy the insurance
how we service the insurance how we
handle claims how we uh make sure we are
enabling them to renew the customer and
uh and so on and so forth so uh we
actually uh
built an app called i'll take care to uh
to help in this whole engagement process
and we have extended this to all of our
retail customers
it's it started just before the pandemic
so you know by the time the pandemic
started it was already in place and that
helped us reach out to our customers in
a in a very seamless way through this
app
but uh
as we as we build features in that we
realize that we have to do a lot of
micro segmentation of our customers and
and do needs analysis of each segment um
so we looked at wellness right so we
brought in some wellness
partners and
the the other aspect is health
as soon as we look at health health is
very closely tied with wellness and as
insurance companies none of us
you know have the expertise to provide
wellness services whereas any wellness
service that we can provide to our
customers
not only helps the customers it helps us
it helps the entire
you know industry and and the entire
country it's it's beyond just making
money out of this i mean health is a is
a very important uh aspect and and we
are a key stakeholder in the whole
health care process
so we've brought in partners who are
wellness partners
and we have integrated them into our
overall journey
when we looked at
this journey we saw that healthcare
starts with opd services everyone does
not just need hospitalization at every
instance so we started uh with something
like telephony consultation with the
doctor and i'm talking during the
pandemic this was a big help
people were so nervous i i'm having a
cough i want to know whether i've got
covet this was constantly a worry that
people had and a lot of our customers
were calling our call center and saying
that i want to go to a hospital but i'm
not finding a hospital
you know bed or even i'm not finding a
doctor who will treat me
if you remembering you know during those
months of march april a lot of doctors
were
you know also
a little bit worried about treating
patients so you know the whole physical
touch was so
uh worrying for everybody and and there
are at the same time there are hugely
you know dedicated doctors who braved
through ovid and uh you know that
obviously they're doctors of all kinds
but the number of doctors were less than
what is available in any case in india
just from a regular visit perspective
sometimes you have to wait months to get
a good doctor
and at that point of time creating this
whole
opd consultation over a telephone really
helped a lot people could
just call up the doctor and and get some
quick advice and if they really needed a
consultation of the physical doctor we
would then enable that and that's why
having a an entire partnership actually
helped quite a bit
now when we when we went beyond this and
we started looking at the needs of of
this one individual who is probably
staying alone at home and has fallen
sick we realized that just doctor
consultation does not help you have to
add pharmacy services so that his
medicine gets delivered at home
then we uh you know we looked at
another segment of customers who are fit
but they are health conscious and they
want to know whether they are
keeping fit at an adequate level so we
we built in features for tracking their
health
and and so on and so forth just expanded
from there we allowed them to track
their activities get their health risk
score and and so on and you know this
approach we are seeing a very positive
start i will say start because you know
as as many others mentioned before
insurance penetration is is quite low in
india and we are giving an app as an
added digital feature so so the number
of people that we've been able to cover
at this point of time is around you know
half a million which is
which is a large number but when you
compare to the you know country of our
size it's it's very small yeah
so uh so on on that part and i i think
uh there are a lot more interesting
things that we can carve out but one one
very interesting aspect that i could uh
figure out is probably collaboration
with uh you know a lot of uh existing
players existing industries we've seen
online doctor consultation being
provided by a lot of companies so
abhishek let me let me call you in here
and and try and uh you know talk about
something like a collaboration between
how
on that front
uh that where do you see this going is
it something where the you know people
like the insurance providers might
actually start building those things or
is it where you know they will start
collaborating and and probably getting
to the you know
probably getting to the thing getting to
the uh you know
solving the problem um along with some
some other players
now that's a great question sagar and
everyone touched upon it right i firmly
believe that uh it's the only way for us
to
capture this opportunity right and when
is it capture this opportunity we think
about the size of our country and the
scale of work that needs to happen with
respect to penetration of insurance
it is impossible
for the limited set of insurance
companies to
build distribution on their own
the only way for us to make this happen
is to take a take a very ecosystem kind
of approach to build awareness to sell
insurance
and to sell all the associated products
that the consumers eventually need
and hence the
insurance companies need to partner
with the intermediary speed brokers or
uh web aggregators also with the ensure
text to make the distribution happen
insure tech partners right for example
plum
we partner a lot with fintech companies
uh with hrms companies to further the
distribution right and a great example
is actually from partnering with razer p
uh to distribute insurance to all the
razor-based payroll users we in fact in
the
in the announcement that herschel and
sachan did yesterday uh where they
announced razer pay rights with an
initiative uh for startups
we partnered with pizza pay one more
time to
offer
insurance for all the startups enjoying
the razor pay rise program completely
complementary right so these kind of
partnerships needs to happen
to capture this opportunity or the scale
of the opportunity that we have and this
kind of penetration or this kind of
partnership will happen in different
dimensions it's not just
insurance company and distribution
companies
partnership it is
ensure tech and
fintech company partnering which is
ensure tech and health tech companies
partnering and maybe a lot many
partnerships that the panelists here can
also talk about sure so let me let me
actually call in
which is
considering that you know one of the one
of the other partnership that i wanted
to talk about is probably the
partnership between uh you know
insurance companies and the brokers and
the web aggregators i believe uh that is
also where we are seeing like a lot of
innovation kind of happening and with uh
uh you know with with a good amount of
ipos happening in i mean in in in this
calendar year with even
uh you know even star uh health kind of
getting uh listed today and even um
pb fintech uh getting listed so a lot of
these uh kind of resemble that the
entire sentiment for for you know the
sector be it for web aggregators is also
very positive for brokers is also
positive but what kind of roles are do
you think uh the brokers play
specifically uh when it comes to you
know the the problems like the reach
because i think one one thing uh that we
all kind of agree uh is that obviously
there are a lot of innovations which are
happening on the front where uh you know
we are trying to get care packages or uh
even trying to you know build up for
making sure that people who are already
you know in the gamut of these insurance
products can actually get benefit right
from their home but uh what about those
uh you know those those kind of reach
related problems and do you think that
uh you know these insurance brokers or
maybe the uh the insurers directly will
have
like a bigger role to play
on on that front
yeah
so
[Music]
i think you were on mute now i can hear
you so yeah
so i was saying there was time when you
know the customer
used to walk in into the insurance
company's office for
other policy or claims that was you know
uh also a phase
but uh now the situation is quite
different where
either the insurer has to reach out
directly to the
uh you know to the customer maybe
remotely uh online
or
uh
possibly there is a intermediary maybe
broker or
the agent actually who has to
probably you know
customer prefer
his presence or maybe prefer to deal
with him or her
so but in both scenario i think
the digital capability i think
is a key to the you know to current uh
operations uh you know uh to be seen as
successful
so uh i see uh brokers role very very
important uh even in today's scenario
because
uh as an insurance company if you had
really
built
scale of the business you you have to be
part of the you know
uh
the ecosystem that you know is uh
prevailing uh you know uh at this point
of time
and uh there are uh you know
various you know line of business which
are controlled
i know by various intermediary uh you
know various for example
uh
the motor business new car or maybe new
vehicle business is largely controlled
by the large brokers and you know which
are
you know maybe
uh representing some of the oem uh
anyway
so uh
so if you have to tap those you have to
approach through them there are older
vehicles which are you know or maybe the
health uh probably mostly it is
happening through
uh the agents
and uh there are you know uh certain
other business which is also happening
through brokers
so i
so what we have to you know
ensure this as insurance companies so
whosoever is interpreting the business
on our behalf
there is a
ease of transaction the
partner is comfortable with us
and the partner is you know as far as
possible digitally equipped and uh there
are no hassles
so to
really survive in this market i think uh
uh
broker's role is very very critical
and
i can say that
the kind of
innovation that is happening at the
distribution side whether the broker or
web aggregator i think is amazing
equal innovation or equal you know
uh equally they are also evolving in
terms of technology and
uh you know making themselves
compatible uh you know to the company's
requirement and the customer requirement
so their role is very very critical and
uh
motor of course uh
a lot of
uh you know
things have changed a lot of
digitalization
digitalization has happened already
uh but uh health some
uh improvement is happening where you
know the broker's role and insurance
companies role
uh you know is significant
but uh there are a lot of non-motor uh
you know other kind of business which is
where
uh law you know a lot of things to be
done and without uh
the contribution of the brokers i think
is really really difficult
at this point of time
i'm sure uh the way
we are the way we go forward i think uh
everything is evolving and
the on the tech side also the
distribution of the you know
higher ticket size
line of business will also
uh get involved evolved
sure so in fact i i want to bring in uh
uh you know chennai and uh even praveen
both of them because i actually have uh
you know uh this this specific thing and
it is it is kind of linked to the health
insurance side of things uh what we what
we've realized is that you know almost
almost all the times when we are talking
about the entire market being under
penetrated uh a lot of it uh has to uh
you know uh has to deal with uh you know
the education
of of uh you know people not being there
so i think uh this is where uh you know
a lot of folks are trying to do uh
various uh variety of things and i just
wanted to throw this question to you
both uh that is there any any specific
thing that uh you know you see
which is working pretty well and uh what
are what are those aspects which are
kind of just taking this specific thing
uh to the next level we've understood
that always the insurance selling has
been
i mean
probably pardon my words but there are
times that people are scared and then
they kind of think about insurance how
do we make sure that it's the other way
around that you know they are actually
thinking about it happily and just going
and purchasing something so that's
that's probably on on
you know the health and life side
uh that that i have uh the specific
questions uh uh considering that
education becomes like a very critical
element uh in that front
should i uh why don't you go first for
this okay
um
when it comes to health insurance
penetration you mentioned that why
aren't people what can we do further so
i have this is my hypothesis honestly
personally about health insurance too
one is uh you know insurance is not
you know a fun thing to talk about
nobody except seeing our buy insurance
so it
while everyone thinks it's impo at the
same time everyone knows it's important
so it's unlikely you'll go somewhere and
say do you think health insurance is
important people will say no no one will
say
so
what happened during covet and that's
the lesson that's the moment of epiphany
for me if i was to say is that in
during covet time importance was
translated into urgency by covert into
action by covet so how do you translate
awareness into action is where we are in
in at least urban india largely up in
india that's one part of the problem and
i think kobe did that
uh second thing that i understood from
covid is that when you give a simple
product but even when you have that
awareness you have that urgency when you
have a product that is so simple
adoption is very easy
uh we in the industry unfortunately have
complicated health insurance products
very complicated even i can't if you ask
me to explain
my own health insurance product to
someone without checking the document
once i will still want to check what all
the wait periods different types of wait
periods different types of exclusions
because that's how the industry is
designed
what we think the need of the r
is first to really simplify health
insurance to create
a really simple product and that's our
own challenge we've taken internally to
create a product that can be explained
in one page of course to be explained to
10 year old seven year olds but to be
explained in one page because even a 40
year old doesn't want to reach three
read three pages
you know they're saying great you know
you guys are very transparent you've
given me a cis but i don't have the
patience to read three pages tell me in
one page i mean i've had my colleagues
from different group companies coming
and telling me this thing that why do
you guys make it so complicated so covet
actually did that and you would hear
from everyone without too much
advertising
the number of covet policies that were
sold on our own website
you know because there was a pull and it
was so easy to understand and why so i
think simplicity of product design and
simplicity of purchase has to it's
something that we haven't cracked in the
industry we have to do that
and the sec second i think is to really
uh
hear the customer
when we started before we started our
business we actually went we did a lot
of research around what the consumer
speak was most of our innovations are
born in what consumers speak was which
was health 241 where the younger
audience was saying i will not claim so
i don't want to buy so we tried to give
them a two for one kind of construct
switch which was a pay as you go product
where you know consumers came to us and
say i don't drive 365 days a year why do
i pay insurance for water 365 days a
year so these were things that the
consumers were telling us so in health
insurance also what we are trying we are
doing now is that post covet we are
actually going back we've commissioned a
large research we've gone back to the
consumer and tried to understand what
are the drivers of consideration what
are the barriers for purchase to really
understand what drives you what makes
you interested in a category what makes
you interested in a brand
what stops you from investing in a
category or engaging with the category
so these are two things two things where
we are acting and i think
the fact that you know you think digital
first helps you innovate and
the third thing that i have learned from
studying some other markets
is that if you want to enter get a foot
in the door with the customer we have to
find a low inertia low friction product
to get a foot in the door and then
upsell and up the value chain so these
are three things that i think
we we are trying to act on work on to
actually uh improve
penetration in this case very very
insightful uh uh i i believe uh
uh uh you know praveen uh
question probably i'll have to uh you
know slightly tweak the you know tweak
the question i think uh on on the
education side uh i kind of covered it
beautifully so on um i mean on on on
this specific piece itself uh
obviously there are a lot more things to
uh to be talked about but there's one
analogy that i always find very
interesting that you know when it comes
to you know people opening up a bank
account it becomes fairly easy for
people to trust uh you know other other
organizations with their own money but
when it comes to you know people having
uh to trust uh you know somebody for uh
for a part of it uh i mean in return
they will actually be uh you know
getting uh
i mean something i mean something
critical in case something goes bad
how is that being uh you know how from a
mentality point of view is that being
conveyed because there are times that if
you convey this to somebody they will
probably understand but uh do you think
from um you know from that point of view
are there uh you know are there any ways
in which we can probably make it uh or
over emphasize this piece and from uh
from from your point of view from your
vantage point is there uh you know any
any specific very interesting thing that
you folks have done uh pertaining to the
education side of things
sure sure uh so i can see uh definitely
this is very very critical because
most of the lot are like uh it's like a
legal lingua for any of us it's like
insurance also sometimes we don't
understand okay and first thing is
imparting this knowledge to the agent
who is actually interrupting the end
user so
uh as part of install we are trying to
have something called launch pad for
them to train because we don't want
missiling see someone is having a pd
okay pre-existing disease right so they
said no you can take this we will cover
but when it comes to claim that is where
the prescription comes okay
so the first and foremost thing is the
one who is purchasing the policy is
fully aware of what he or she is buying
what is covered what is not covered
because once they are clear with that
okay whatever the premium that they make
okay and when there is a claim there is
no frictions because they are aware of
that okay and there are like even uh
irda has brought certain uh regulations
where the exclusions you can add for
example someone says okay these diseases
okay you don't you can exclude from my
policy okay so uh predominantly coming
to the education part of it right uh
both the agent and end user
should be aware of all the terms and
conditions and everything they should uh
acknowledge and one of the key thing
that we do is called daily verification
card that means someone sold okay we
call that customer ensure that they are
aware of all these terms whether they
have been explained by the agent
okay
so that there is no missiling
okay so this is how we have to protect
like see for example why all these
regulators come because someone goes and
promises something and it is again
between the end user and the insurance
company right so we have to we have a
responsible role to play in this field
to ensure that the end customer is aware
of everything and they acknowledge and
they'll purchase the policy
sure sure i think miss selling uh and
those kind of things uh also become like
very very uh very critical to be aware
of uh i think i'll probably you know
draw a segway considering that uh you
know
we're kind of uh you know at the 48th
minute i'll i'll probably try and uh you
know bring in some something which is
very close to uh you know me which is
which is around the payment side of
things and uh you know one of the things
that i've actually heard from a lot of
people is is around you know recurring
payments being a very big problem and
whenever i sit across the table with a
lot of uh insurers a lot of them have
said that you know what uh uh this is uh
you know this this always becomes a very
big challenge for us to kind of get
uh you know get get the renewals out
there so anyone um just wanted to
understand from from uh you know i said
lombard's point of view is it is it
something which is like a really big
problem and and you know with the new
regulations which are you know which are
coming around say uh the you know the
recurring payments on card transactions
is it is it where you are actually
seeing some some of that taking a hit
and how are you kind of tackling that
from you know from from your vantage
point
hey anyone you're on mute yeah sorry um
so what we've done payments is a big
issue it's um
on one side i think it's very
interesting that india is probably one
of the got one of the most advanced
payment ecosystems in the in the world
and at the same time we have uh built
our you know pretty much most of our
payment infrastructure assuming that the
end customer has a smartphone
only about uh you know half roughly half
of the country actually has a smartphone
so we are
we are looking at
another half of india who cannot avail
of the of the huge infrastructure that
they've created for payments
um you talked about recurring payments
that's that's been a a really big point
of debate internally within within icc
lombard as well as
uh with our payment partner which is
razer pay and
we took a conscious decision
you know way back when the first
guideline from rbi came in
that
we will not over invest in recurring
payments until we are convinced that
about three things on one side we want
to be convinced that the technology is
accessible to a large majority of
customers
on the second side the technology is
absolutely secure and and
it's meeting all the regulations and on
the third side we have a huge demand so
when we first tried our recurring
payments um
this was for two-wheeler again the
thought process was that um a
two-wheeler is a very small amount of
payment and as shanna mentioned that
it's not something that people you know
wake up every morning and say let me go
and ensure my vehicle or or my health
and suddenly somebody realizes in the
last day that hey my renewals is due and
i've not really done renewals so can we
look at a situation where when you buy
the insurance it's anyway very small
amount of money can you get
a mandate that the renewals will happen
year after year
we launched this with a very low
investment but we launched in one
specific market
which is uh what we call the affinity
market so if you go to a petrol pump you
could actually get your two wheeler
insured
by somebody standing out there so we
kind of launched it in that market um
usually anything on the two-wheelers we
we look at thousands of policies every
day after a whole year we have got 40
mandates 4-0
not 40 000 40 mandates um so so then we
had a again an internal uh you know
thinking and and everybody said you know
what you guys chose the wrong product
because
hey i mean vehicle people can sell off
nobody wants to really ensure year after
year let's look at health because
of course health is something that you
want to really ensure year after year
so now we became a little bit more uh by
then we also built up this three three
point agenda that all these three have
to be satisfied so we said great we are
going to launch health
and uh
what we did was we said that we are
going to only launch the collection
bandit collection sorry not collection
the mandate so we will get the mandates
will not build collection we'll get the
mandates
and we had our internal targets
when we discussed this with the sales
team and the distribution partners
everybody said health is so important
and this whole process of recurring
payments will help so much we will get
you know 20 to 25 percent people will
actually
get give us the mandates we took a
target of five percent and at the end of
a three month trial period we did not
even hit one percent
so this recurring payment and and then
we analyzed actually there are reasons
for this and uh there are many other
um insurance players who have done some
of this analysis a lot of that is
public publicly available some of it is
not i will i'll speak only on what is
available on the public domain um so one
of the one of the big challenges that um
exists in health insurance compared to
life insurance in life insurance you
actually have a true emi or equated
annual installment or or whatever so the
entire the underwriting happens for the
entire life and if it's a term product
you actually define the total unwriting
cost and you are then um setting it up
you know year after year and so on in
health
you have cohort based underwriting and
the day you actually do a claim your
cohort changes from a person who has not
done any claim to a person who has now
done a claim and we cannot predict which
cohort you will belong to
also there are there are other diseases
that you can incur and of course when
you are
fit and healthy you know the cost of
providing health care to you is less
as and when you go forward the cost
increases the second dimension is the
innovation itself actually innovation
itself becomes a problem for payments
because every year all of us all the
industry players are innovating products
is laughing abhishek and us and he
mentioned about the whole partnership
between you know plum razor pay and and
the underlying product is a lombard
product which is sold and
that's an innovation that just came out
now if somebody wants to
look at that product and then he might
think that why do i need to buy my own
personal health health product and there
are obviously reasons on both sides but
as soon as an innovative product comes
in the person may not want to continue
with the old product that he has i i
will talk about myself personally when i
take my own personal health insurance
from isa lombard i have a two-year
policy and i took it in my you know
birth month which is in august um in
2020.
in november 2020 we launched a product
which is i mean the day the product was
launched i was literally you know
screaming at myself why am i not going
to be able to and obviously it doesn't
make sense to buy a second product
we call this the new comprehensive
health insurance and and it has
components of travel insurance in it it
has components of various things which
you know again
the kind of life i leave that is
absolutely perfect for me and i i just
bought something two years back two
months back so
these are the challenges why payment is
not a problem i want to make it clear
the payment is the easier part the rbi
regulation while that
impacts theoretically and it impacts a
lot in let's say the life insurance
industry because there the the
underwriting is such that you are
underwriting for the whole life yep our
handwriting is
it can be extended to whole like but it
depends on on various other factors
which change you a on a year by year
basis
sure so i think everyone uh very very
interesting insights i i believe we are
we are running out of time i'll probably
still squeeze in a very quick one-liner
from you all i i think a lot of people
are entrepreneurs who are out there so
i'll probably uh you know
probably ask one very uh one one liner
sort of advice from you all uh in terms
of any messages for people who are
trying to do something in the show tech
space
starting with you and everyone any
advice for people
sure i think uh you know the ensure tech
space is a very very important partner
for us for all of us for all of us who
are players in the health insurance uh
we work with at least 40 to 15 show tech
players including razer pay including
plum and various other and from the from
the razer pay and plum which are the
unicorns to the to the smallest level
startup we have partnership with
everybody so my only advice to everyone
will be innovate find out innovative new
products as an insurance company we
always look for innovative solutions
which we will be happy to partner with
great uh which is over to you any any um
any
uh you know any any one statement advice
for entrepreneurs who are out there uh
trying to do something in the enshore
tech space
yeah so most of us are you know
manufacturers
of the products and uh
there are
definitely you know from
manufacturing line to the
to end user i think there are a lot of
uh
gaps and there are lot of you know areas
which need to be filled
and that is where i think the role of
you know in showtech
and the you know solution providers
definitely
you know is required second
uh also on the uh you know artificial
intelligence uh and because as uh you
know another one was mentioning
uh
uh in recurring payment actually there
is no issue of payment per se but the
issue is more on the underwriting side
you know how do we reassess the customer
and
then you know
price rightly
so i think
all these uh new age technology will
support in all those you know
underwriting is the major problem for us
in any non-life companies and this is
where a lot of solutions are required
you know from the intro talk and the
solution providers
it should i um
last words from your side for for
so i would say that there are three
participants in large participants in
insurance
one is the consumer the other is the
distribution
most of the times and the third is
insurer
amongst all these stakeholders find
the gaps
find you have razor sharp focus on the
problem you're trying to solve
don't try to solve everything find the
problem use trying to solve and then
figure who your collaborators should be
and if your collaborators you find that
are going to be insurance companies
please talk to them before you
go to market because there will be
enough people who will be willing to
collaborate with you in going to market
itself
perfect perfect so i think uh uh there
are good amount of advices from people
ravine you want to add something
yeah uh one
key scope that we have is with respect
to bite-sized and behavioral driven okay
today we still not have seen behavioral
driven products in the market and irda
provides a sandbox environment okay so
people can come with new ideas and
they're okay to amend their regulations
in that space and the next big thing is
the claim so so everyone today is one of
the biggest thing is a claim so if you
can make claim hassle-free journey i
think nothing like that so these are the
areas people can concentrate on we
inside also will be focusing on that oh
nice so i think yeah in fact sandbox was
one thing that i wanted to cover but uh
yeah in the rest of time we could not uh
we could not talk about it a lot but
yeah very interesting point i think last
uh uh
uh i will take your take um
yeah if you're an entrepreneur like me
uh who had zero experience with
insurance before starting the company i
would recommend four things that we did
right talk to your customers extensively
to understand
what you are trying to solve
talk to players in the ecosystem to
learn the business to learn how you are
going to build it with them
number three build an understanding of
regulations it is very important figure
out what license you need get the
license don't take shortcuts and number
four
insurance is a very unique industry
where you require a lot of patience and
persistence so be ready to play the long
game no shortcuts
no shortcuts i think uh that's that's
very precise um uh with with that i i
think uh we are out of time there are a
lot of people picking me that hey this
is this is uh this is kind of going
beyond the beyond the r mark so thank
you so much all the panelists it's all
it was really amazing to actually get
good amount of knowledge from
from you all thank you thank you over to
you kanan
thank you sagar and thank you everyone
uh for your time
uh this was very informative panel i
think i best summed up by i think one of
the panelists said how do you translate
awareness into action is my takeaway
from that and personally i often think
about how do you translate action into
profit and then after that how do you
translate profit into happiness is my
main concern but again thank you guys so
much for your time uh for everybody
watching uh we are almost at the end of
fdx 2021 day two our next panel is on
the blockchain and cryptocurrency boom
which will be beginning just shortly so
that's all for this session i'll see you
guys over in the next one thank you
everyone
[Music]